<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>What's My Pro-Life Line?</title>
    <link>https://facebook.com/whatsmyprolifeline</link>
    <description>
      We suggest things you can say to promote and defend the pro-life position with love and kindness.
    </description>
    <language>en-us</language>
  <item><title>Glad You’re Okay</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/glad-youre-okay/</link><guid>f6a6f321-d449-436e-8b04-ec15ca197843</guid><pubDate>2019-03-24</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/glad-youre-okay/glad-youre-okay-1-940.png"&gt;It’s not always time to make a pro-life argument. Remember to show compassion and listen to understand. Abortion is a really sensitive topic! Be prepared for any conversation to emotionally affect people, and understand that if someone is upset, they’re not prepared to think reasonably. They will probably reject any argument you make, and even view arguments as personal attacks. We don’t want to upset people, so when you’re talking with someone who may be emotionally affected by the conversation, it’s a good idea to spend a lot of time building trust and common ground. You may not even get to make a single argument in your first few conversations with someone! That’s okay. You’re still making positive progress even if all you’re doing is moving toward an environment where your conversation partner feels safe enough to think about what you’re saying with an open mind.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/glad-youre-okay/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_empathy</description></item><item><title>Self-Directed Development</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/self-directed-development/</link><guid>bd04e90d-d1f1-4887-ab84-40ca60173ab7</guid><pubDate>2019-03-24</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/self-directed-development/self-directed-development-0-940.png"&gt;The fetus references her own DNA to develop its own organs. The mother provides things like food, water, and shelter. For more information about why this point is important, check out this essay by law professor Richard Stith: https://www.firstthings.com/web-exclusives/2006/11/stith-arguing-with-pro-choicer&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/self-directed-development/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_biology #WMPLL_lifebegins</description></item><item><title>Flatworms Don’t Have Hearts</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/flatworms-dont-have-hearts/</link><guid>7f75e1e4-c1b7-4084-b3a3-cd17541bf2d1</guid><pubDate>2019-03-24</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/flatworms-dont-have-hearts/flatworms-dont-have-hearts-0-940.png"&gt;Following fertilization, the zygote undergoes cellular reproduction, responds to stimuli, and converts food into energy. These are the sort of features that biologists look for to establish life, not a heartbeat. It’s debatable whether viruses are alive, but it seems pretty clear that a zygote is already biologically alive.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It may be helpful to emphasize that at this stage of the conversation, we aren’t yet saying anything philosophical about how valuable a zygote is or how we ought to treat zygotes. We’re just saying that biologically speaking, a zygote is a living organism.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/flatworms-dont-have-hearts/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_biology #WMPLL_lifebegins</description></item><item><title>Abortion Is Never Safe</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/abortion-is-never-safe/</link><guid>8db7efea-0130-4de1-8996-12ba5dd093f4</guid><pubDate>2019-03-24</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/abortion-is-never-safe/abortion-is-never-safe-0-940.png"&gt;It’s extremely important to show compassion when dealing with this sensitive topic. Your top priority should be making it clear that you care about women, not just about fetuses.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/abortion-is-never-safe/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_politics #WMPLL_womenshealth #WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>Incest</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/incest/</link><guid>a45cc2d8-4e7c-471f-8747-5f1e5249102c</guid><pubDate>2019-03-24</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/incest/incest-0-940.png"&gt;Different people have different reasons for thinking abortion is justified in cases of pregnancy resulting from incestuous relationships. Some people focus on the status of the mother as a victim of a crime; this is similar to the proposal that abortion should be allowed in cases of rape. In reality, the child is another victim of the crime, and he or she should not be blamed or punished.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Other people focus on possible birth defects of the child; this is similar to the proposal that abortion should be allowed if the preborn child is diagnosed with a disability. In reality, we should support and care for people with disabilities, not kill them.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/incest/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_ethics</description></item></channel>
</rss>