<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>What's My Pro-Life Line?</title>
    <link>https://facebook.com/whatsmyprolifeline</link>
    <description>
      We suggest things you can say to promote and defend the pro-life position with love and kindness.
    </description>
    <language>en-us</language>
  <item><title>Abortion Is Never Safe</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/abortion-is-never-safe/</link><guid>8db7efea-0130-4de1-8996-12ba5dd093f4</guid><pubDate>2019-03-24</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/abortion-is-never-safe/abortion-is-never-safe-0-940.png"&gt;It’s extremely important to show compassion when dealing with this sensitive topic. Your top priority should be making it clear that you care about women, not just about fetuses.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/abortion-is-never-safe/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_politics #WMPLL_womenshealth #WMPLL_society</description></item><item><title>Incest</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/incest/</link><guid>a45cc2d8-4e7c-471f-8747-5f1e5249102c</guid><pubDate>2019-03-24</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/incest/incest-0-940.png"&gt;Different people have different reasons for thinking abortion is justified in cases of pregnancy resulting from incestuous relationships. Some people focus on the status of the mother as a victim of a crime; this is similar to the proposal that abortion should be allowed in cases of rape. In reality, the child is another victim of the crime, and he or she should not be blamed or punished.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Other people focus on possible birth defects of the child; this is similar to the proposal that abortion should be allowed if the preborn child is diagnosed with a disability. In reality, we should support and care for people with disabilities, not kill them.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/incest/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_ethics</description></item><item><title>Thalidomide</title><link>https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/thalidomide/</link><guid>1647a007-17e5-4fe7-9a57-067b4f2ffc66</guid><pubDate>2019-03-24</pubDate><description>&lt;img src="https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/thalidomide/thalidomide-0-940.png"&gt;Thalidomide is a drug that was used in the late 1950s to treat morning sickness in pregnant women. Unfortunately, as it turns out, treating pregnant women with thalidomide causes severe deformities in their children. Many thousands of people alive today are still suffering the effects of thalidomide.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Most people agree that pregnant women should not be allowed to take thalidomide if they plan to give birth. This demonstrates that some ethical principles still apply even when someone is inside someone else’s body. If the person you’re talking to bites the bullet and says that pregnant women should be allowed to take thalidomide to treat morning sickness, ask about a hypothetical scenario in which a pregnant woman does not have morning sickness. In this hypothetical, unrealistic scenario, the woman is considering taking thalidomide anyway, because she actually wants her child to be deformed so that she’ll get attention. Almost everybody will agree that this hypothetical woman should not take thalidomide.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;See this post on our website: https://whatsmyprolifeline.com/posts/thalidomide/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;#WMPLL_bodilyautonomy #WMPLL_ethics #WMPLL_womenshealth</description></item></channel>
</rss>